{"_id": "45080c42", "question": "What are other solutions to a Transient Stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "31538580", "question": "What is the difference between a hemorrhagic stroke, an ischemic stroke, and a transient ischemia stroke?", "answers": "There are changing names for these things but I will try to answer\nA stroke is an infarction of brain tissue killing it in the center of the tissue and leaving a margin around the death of semi living tissue. Strokes have different causes. Ischemic , lack of oxygen , or embolic, also lack of oxygen but caused by a small clot that flew into the brain artery and blocked blood flow. Tumors and foreign bodies can cause blockages as well.\nIf this blockage lasts more than about 15 minutes it it pretty certain that part of the brain tissue will die. Dead brain means loss of the nerves in that part of the brain.\nHow long does this blockage last ?\nDoes the part of the brain have some rapid alternative blood supply?\nWill the clot dissolve before it kills brain tissue and restores some blood supply. ?\nWhat happens to dead brain tissue ?\nA Reversible Ischemic neurological deficit (RIND, or TIA,). Has usually meant that neurological loss is temporary and has mostly recovered to normal within 24 hours. ( this may be old school speak ).\nA completed Stroke is a neurological deficit that lasts more than 24 hours. It may change and improve a bit but it leaves residual neurological loss .\nHemorrhagic stroke can be several things.\nThe dead tissue bleeds into itself or expands and hurts other tissue\nThe small brain artery actually bursts and blood into brain tissue that expands and puts pressure on normal brain tissue. This is often because of a brain aneurism. ( like a small defect in the Artery that forms a balloon in the vessel and it bursts )"}
{"_id": "6b5e8184", "question": "How do neurologists rule-out a transient ischemic attack or \"mini-stroke\"?", "answers": "To Dr. Soso and Dr. Kinnard comments I would add that you also need a cardiology workup with Holter monitor and other vascular studies to identify a possible source for an embolus and/or arrhythmia.\nYour ability to give a good history seems to show you are probably bright. But your refusal to get a proper evaluation and followup is troubling.\nYou don’t have a diagnosis yet! Be smart and have a proper workup."}
{"_id": "e91ebd96", "question": "What's the difference between a mini stroke, a transient ischemic attack (TIA), and a headrush that leads to syncope (fainting)?", "answers": "A mini stroke and a TIA are essentially the same. You feel some numbness/weakness in half of your body, potentially have dizzy spells, lose some ability possibly like speech, etc but things resolve relatively quickly, say within 24 hours or maybe a few days. Have a work colleague who had a minor stroke one night, everything was back to \"normal\" the next morning.\nA typical stroke on the other hand ranging from (big to major to massive, etc) depending on the damage, can lead to hemiplegia (half-body paralysis), aphasia (loss of speech) or other life-changing injuries that can take months to resolve. I had my major stroke 7 months ago, and i'm still recovering, and rehabilitating, and still learning to walk \"normal\" again.\nSorry, can't really speak about headrushes that lead to fainting.. But re your episodes, I really think you should visit the hospital, if in case you had a ministroke, your chances of having a real stroke is really big, and boy, you'd want to avoid that in way possible. I believe from what I was told, an MRI or CT scan would reveal past strokes, even mini ones... i hope you have yourself checked."}
{"_id": "5ad9c2c0", "question": "If they say that there is no blood flowing throughout the brain, then how about a stroke or a TIA (transient ischemic attack)?", "answers": "I’m not sure what you are asking with this question, but I will try to answer, based on what I assume you are getting at.\nThe condition of “no blood flowing throughout the brain” is what one would see in the case of cardiac arrest, where the heart stops pumping. That would cause severe brain damage within a few minutes, if blood flow were not restored. The brain depends on the circulation for a constant supply of nutrients and oxygen.\nIn the case of stroke or TIA, blood flow is reduced, but only to a part of the brain, not the brain as a whole. It need not necessarily be reduced to zero to cause symptoms.\nNormally, cerebral blood flow is maintained at ~50 mL per 100 g of brain tissue per minute. A fall to 30 ml/100g/min would very likely cause symptoms.\nThe body puts a premium on maintaining a constant blood flow to the brain via the process called autoregulation. If you are interested in learning more about this, here is a link to get you started.\nControl of Cerebral Blood Flow"}
{"_id": "f3b25617", "question": "Why are Transient Ischemic Attacks precursors to full blown strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8b20b461", "question": "What is the average lenghth of time between suffering an Transient Ischemic Stroke and the occurence of a major stroke?", "answers": "A TIA often precedes a major ischemic stroke by a month or less. Prompt assessment of a TIA and following medical recommendations may prevent further problems.\nMy radiologist found signs that I’d suffered TIA’s that I wasn’t aware of in his assessment of the CT I had when I first arrived with a major stroke. I wish I’d noticed and paid attention.\nStrokes leave permanent damage and recovery is very difficult. It has been almost three years of hard work and I’m still recovering. Everyone remarks on my “remarkable” recovery, but I’m still clumsy, off balance and I fall far too often.\nIf you have a TIA, pay attention!"}
{"_id": "eb165089", "question": "What is Transient Global Amnesia and does it imitate a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b0022269", "question": "What is the difference between a stroke and a transient ischemic attack?", "answers": "A transient ischemic attack has the same origins as that of an ischemic stroke, the most common type of stroke. In an ischemic stroke, a clot blocks the blood supply to part of your brain. In a transient ischemic attack, unlike a stroke, the blockage is brief, and there is no permanent damage."}
{"_id": "b16424cc", "question": "Which is a modifiable risk factor for transient ischemic attacks and ischemi strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6cb88df0", "question": "Can mini-stroke/transient ischemic attack last minutes and cause numbness in both hands? I had darkness in vision, numbness and tingling in 2 hands, was sweating. Blood pressure was low. This happened on 1 day of my period and accompanied cramps.", "answers": "While missing a lot of info this certainly doesn’t sound like a TIA.\nMost likely scenario is the following. Abdominal cramping can trigger what’s known as a cardioinhibitory or vasovagal reflex, initially slowing heart rate and lowering blood pressure. I’m not sure what you mean by darkened vision. but this could be from low blood pressure.\nAs the body tries to react to this decrease in blood pressure it releases catecholamines and other substances that increase the blood pressure but also cause sweating, hyperventilation (rapid breathing) and anxiety.\nThe symmetric hand numbness is characteristic of hyperventilation induced hypocalcemia, where the low CO2 in the body drives calcium into cells which in produce this symptom called parestheshia.\nHypoglycemia (low blood sugar), nausea and dehydration could cause a similar picture.\nNone of this should be taken as medical advice - I don’t know nearly enough of your medical history to rule out something more sinister - would see a doctor if you are concerned."}
{"_id": "bd6f072d", "question": "What is the difference between a stroke and TIA?", "answers": "A transient ischemic attack (TIA), also called a mini-stroke, occurs when a blood vessel in the brain is blocked for just a short while, but long enough to produce ischemia and cause some reversible brain dysfunction. Low brain oxygen and nutrients mean that the affected brain part begins to lose function.\nThe blockade gets lifted sooner than later and the affected part of the brain resumes its function. This can happen when a clot dissolves to allow a reflow of blood to the affected brain part. The body has its natural enzyme called plasmin that breaks down fibrin in the clot.\nIn a stroke, however, the blockade is not temporary but persists and the ensuing prolonged ischemia causes an irreversible damage, resulting in the death of the affected tissue or an infarct. If clot dissolves when severe damage has already been done, the reflow of blood, on the contrary, will have a catastrophic effect, instead. Calcium overload leads to free radical production and this facilitates cell death."}
{"_id": "e3794295", "question": "What causes heat stroke?", "answers": "Heat Stroke is a term too loosely used. Properly defined it is a stroke caused by the heat. So this means brain tissue actually dies (often the patient does as well).\nSo what causes it? Heat. Too much heat. The body has several mechanisms to cope with heat;\nnumber 1 is avoidance- So we move out of the sun into the shade. Jump into a pool or shower, A/C on, hat, fan. What if you can’t? You are an infant in a car, prisoner in a cell, passed out due to drugs or alcohol, alzheimers patient, bed ridden nursing home patient. Well then the temp of your brain raises. Once it gets in the 104–5 range it starts to die and unless someone intervenes so do you\nnumber 2 is sweating. So on a hot day you swet. You swet a lot. Swetting keeps the body temperature down however only until you run out of swet. Then you develope heat exhaustion and you either faint or revert to #1 avoidance.\nnumber 3 is vasodilation. You blood is shunted to the skin and the skin blood vessels dilate. So the skin becomes a large radiator. It helps but if the sun is beating down on the skin or there is not enough fluid in the system then well it can’t improve things."}
{"_id": "4381d63e", "question": "What time of day do most strokes occur?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9d50dfa2", "question": "How does a brain stroke happen?", "answers": "To put it as simply as possible there are two types of stroke namely ischemic and haemorrhagic...any factor that causes decreased blood supply to a particular area of the brain leads to ischemic stroke and symptoms pertaining to that particular region of the brain..any factor that increases the pressure of the blood flow through a particular vessel in the brain leads to rupture of the small vessel and causes haemorrhagic stroke...ischemic stroke most commonly caused due to an emboli blocking an end artery...while haemorrhagic stroke is most commonly caused due to uncontrolled hypertension.."}
{"_id": "d2664046", "question": "At what age do most strokes occur?", "answers": "Strokes affect people of all ages, including foetuses. Ischemic strokes are more common in the elderly and hemorrhagic strokes more common in younger people. I had a hemorrhagic stroke in my late 50’s and was delighted to find that I was considered “younger”."}
{"_id": "07cc6016", "question": "Can you get a stroke from having aortic valve disease?", "answers": "Yes but that depends on what sort of aortic arch “disease” your talking about. If it’s a congenital coarctation malformation,Aortic stenosis, aneurism or aortic stricture it can cause areas of restricted or pooled blood flow. Technically yes anytime you slow dwell time in blood vessels tiny emboli can develop. In the case of the Aorta it can cause emboli to get thrown up the carotid artery and cause strokes (Aka emboli or embolic showers) in the brain. Often if this is discovered it’s highly recommended to take long term anticoagulants. Surgery or minimal invasive procedures are often recommended.\nI want to stress that although concerning, this kind of disease can be well monitored managed and followed up on. You may need to see one or more specialists. Find a good health provider doctor,nurse practitioner or physicians assistant and start with a full health physical H&P (history and physical exam) People can live long relatively healthy lives with Aortic arch problems."}
{"_id": "a3512764", "question": "Can a hemorrhagic stroke occur to teenagers?", "answers": "Haemorragic stroke can occur at any age.\nThe most common cause of intracerebral haemorrage is hypertension. This is usually seen in adults who have hypertension. The haemorrage is usually in the putamen or Thalamus. Teenagers also can have hypertension due to secondary causes like renal artery stenosis, chronic kidney disease etc which can make teenagers prone for hypertensive bleeds rarely.\nTeenagers are more likely to develop haemorragic strokes due to conditions like aneurisms, arterio venous malformations, cavernomas, coagulation disorders like hemophilia, low platelet counts, subarachnoid Haemorrage, haemorrage into a tumor or an infarct, use of anticoagulants etc..\nThe epidemic of abuse of the so-called 'designer drugs' amphetamine, cocaine and ecstasy is fast replacing traditional aetiological factors as the largest cause of intracerebral haemorrhage among young adults. Traditional teaching is that these represent hypertensive haemorrhages. Recent reports, however, have indicated that these patients may harbour underlying vascular malformations."}
{"_id": "e41e454a", "question": "How do Strokes occur and how do they effect the human brain and body?", "answers": "The term “stroke” when referring to the brain describes two very different scenarios: the most common (maybe 90%) of strokes are caused by an embolism, a blood clot in an artery feeding the brain which slows or entirely stops blood flow in that artery, killing the brain structure dependent on that blood flow. The other kind of “stroke”, much less common (about 10%) is called an aneurysm (which can occur anywhere in the body) or a brain bleed. There are two kinds of aneurysms: the blood vessel has a weakness in the wall that causes it to balloon outward until it breaks, flooding the brain with blood, and a collapse inward that causes a tear in the blood vessel, same result, blood flooding the interstitial spaces of the brain and insufficient blood flow to the brain structure through normal delivery channels, so that brain structure suffers cell death.\nBecause an embolism induced brain stroke and a brain aneurysm stroke can have the same symptoms (at first), it is a risk to inject the chemical that dissolves blood clots because it can make a brain bleed even worse.\nA stroke can be so mild you don’t even notice it, until they keep occurring and finally symptoms appear. Depending on where it occurs, there are a great variety of symptoms, you can look them up."}
{"_id": "52d2481e", "question": "Does a stroke occur due to immense thinking?", "answers": "No.\nBut immense thinking can happen prior to stroke. Immense thinking means brains gets stuck. That will happen when other parts of the brain stop functioning."}
{"_id": "a772f193", "question": "When do most procedure-related in-hospital strokes occur?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1130931b", "question": "Can heat stroke occur despite adequate hydration?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5abb4a02", "question": "Is there a higher likelihood for a stroke to occur in certain regions of the brain or do strokes occur equally in all areas?", "answers": "This seems like a good website: http://www.strokecenter.org/professionals/brain-anatomy/blood-vessels-of-the-brain/\nGeneral anatomy: The brain vasculature is composed of the anterior circulation (up your neck via the internal carotid from aorta that branches to form the anterior cerebral artery and middle cerebral) and the posterior circulation (from two vertebral arteries that form the basilar artery, which eventually gives rise to the posterior cerebral arteries). The anterior and posterior circulations are connected via the posterior communicating arteries.\nThere are also two major types of strokes: ischemic (85%) and hemorrhagic (15%). The major risk factors of ischemic stroke are smoking, high cholesterol, high blood pressure, diabetes, and atrial fibrillation (heart arrhythmia). There are three main subtypes of ischemic stroke too (thrombosis, embolism, and hypoperfusion).\nFor simplicity's sake to answer your question, I'll stick to the most common arteries to get an embolic stroke. The most common arteries to get blocked off by an embolus is the middle cerebral (~75%) followed by somewhere along the posterior circulation (~20%) and then the anterior circulation (~5%)."}
{"_id": "6fec5703", "question": "What makes a case of a stroke occur in someone who likes to exercise?", "answers": "Stroke can be caused by a lifestyle or habits like ,Smoking, carrying too much weight round the belly and being too fond of alcohol but it is not an overnight thing.rather they gradually increase your risk over a lifetime."}
{"_id": "494b6764", "question": "What time of day do most heart attacks and strokes occur?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e8e25bda", "question": "How does a suction stroke occur in an IC engine? What causes it to occur?", "answers": "Either it is attained by using electric motors or like the conventional method by kick start. Later is continued due to momentum within crank.\nThe pressure difference is required to make it happen. Suction stroke of the piston begins at top dead center (T.D.C.) and ends at bottom dead center (B.D.C.). In this stroke the intake valve must be in the open position while the piston pulls an air-fuel mixture into the cylinder by producing vacuum pressure into the cylinder through its downward motion. The piston is moving down as air is being sucked in by the downward motion against the piston. When the piston starts going downward the volume starts increasing resulting in decrease of pressure inside engine cylinder so the movement of air-fuel mixture is from high pressure to low pressure, so it starts suction of air-fuel mixture inside engine cylinder."}
{"_id": "141026c0", "question": "Can heat stroke occur while exercising in the gym in an air conditioned room?", "answers": "Exertional heat stroke due to metabolic heat production can happen in an air conditioned space due to clothing, drugs, certain personality types, strenuous activity under direction, and dehydration."}
{"_id": "0cc2ae79", "question": "Why does a heat stroke occur in a hot and humid environment?", "answers": "The bodies way of cooling down is by evaporation of sweat. If the humidity is so high in a hot climate that the sweat cannot evaporate then the body heats above its working temperature this is heat stroke. Heat exhaustion is just caused by unbearable heat."}
{"_id": "69f2fb3f", "question": "Mri showed a white spot in my brain where the stroke occurred. What were the 4 other places I saw?", "answers": "If you made it to the ER quickly enough the first “white spot” is the initial lesion site.\nThe other areas affected that the MRI picks up hours/days later is the inflammation damage around the lesion site (if it’s an ischemic stroke). It can affect different ventricles; nerves and lobes of the brain.\nSince we don’t have a MRI to tell, no telling what 4 other areas you saw."}
{"_id": "11c9b51a", "question": "Which type of stroke occurs when the flow of blood to the brain is blocked?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "198784aa", "question": "Have scientists ever used an fMRI to watch a stroke occurring in e.g. a rat? And have it in slow motion?", "answers": "Real-time imaging of different aspects of a stroke?\nYes, with several methods (this is by no means a complete list, just papers that happened to be in my personal reference collection already)\nHigh-resolution in vivo optical imaging of\nstroke\ninjury and repair - PubMed\nMagnetic Particle Imaging for Real-Time Perfusion Imaging in Acute\nStroke\n- PubMed\nWith fMRI? Not sure fMRI is the best tool for a “real-time” picture of stroke. fMRI is based on the BOLD (blood oxygenation level dependent) signal, which is affected by a number of physiological parameters — and an acute stroke would affect all of those parameters. So you would certainly see a change in the BOLD signal due to the reduction in blood flow, but that would just be a part of the signal. Every other physiological parameter that’s tied up in the BOLD signal would also be affected, which would make interpretation particularly difficult. (more detailed discussion at this article: Functional magnetic resonance imaging in chronic ischaemic\nstroke\n(of course, the messiness of the BOLD signal hasn’t stopped researchers from using fMRI before ;)"}
{"_id": "248a61be", "question": "If strokes occur on both sides of the brain, how much time does a person need to recover fully?", "answers": "It depends on the extent the brain has suffered and the kinds of problems it has left you with. Some people have trouble walking, speaking or serve forms of these. this can take a long time but takes about 6 months with therapy to improve considerably."}
{"_id": "4c0cc037", "question": "Which kind of stroke occurs when an artery supplying blood is blocked by a blood clot?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "60c37c72", "question": "What are the chances of helping a 93 year old stroke patient communicate? Comprehension is still intact, she’s been nonverbal, and uncharacteristicly aggressive. Stroke occurred over a year ago. Speech therapy hasn’t really attempted much effort.", "answers": "Find a different SLP, one that specializes in communication and elder care."}
{"_id": "8b856475", "question": "How does a doctor pinpoint a time-frame for when a stroke occurred if it happened years ago?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a54c4814", "question": "Does a small stenosis of the distal portion of the A1 segment of the anterior cerebral artery pose a significant risk of future stroke occurring in that area?", "answers": "It depends. One must first understand the miracle of anatomy known as the Circle of Willis. You will then understand the multitude of divisions of cerebral circulation derived from this unique cerebrovascular structure. The anterior branches of the Circle of Willis intuitively perfuse the frontal lobes of the brain. The anatomy varies considerably from one individual to another regarding dominant flow. The designer invented ingenious methods of collateral/workaround flow when even one small region of brain is injured."}
{"_id": "0115637e", "question": "What is the downward piezo actuator velocity for a 4μm piezo stroke occurring in 0.057μs? Also, what is the average speed of a switch closing when the switch travels 20mm in0.002 seconds?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4990f76e", "question": "When a step leader joins with any upward step and return stroke occurs in the lightning process, what happens to other upward steps, and how do other downward steps illuminate? Do all downward steps illuminate at the same time?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8f21bd5c", "question": "What are the leading risk factors for having a stroke?", "answers": "If you can answer this in a Quora answer, I’d say you deserve the Nobel’s Prize in Medicine!\nIn some cases, it’s obvious what caused a stroke: if somebody’s obese, has really high blood pressure, is really old, etc., it’s pretty clear-cut.\nBut I was 115 pounds, 90/60, and 24 years old when I had my stroke. My doctors looked at me, referred me to a cardiologist for another test, which was negative, and told me to go on my way. “The chance of you having a subsequent stroke is very small,” they assured me.\nSix months later, I was back in the hospital with another one. =(\nAbout six months after THAT, I was able to peer out from beneath my lead jacket of fatigue and pick my head up enough to wonder WHY I’d had a second one. It’d be nice to figure it out, I wagered, to prevent a third one. At that point, I’d already decided that if I had another one, JUST LET ME DIE.\nMy speech therapist referred me to a neurologist at the big city hospital nearby. In retrospect, he was nuts, but he did decide to perform a test just to check for certain that the cardiologist I’d originally seen hadn’t missed anything. (The first test, a TEE — trans esophageal echocardiogram — checked for a hole in my heart by sticking a camera down my throat look to look at my heart. The second test, a TCD — transcranial doppler — shot minuscule bubbles into my arm via an IV and listened to my brain to see if any of them made it up there.) Lo and behold, it dinged! I had a hole in my heart that allowed bubbles/clots/etc to pass through a ventricle and into my brain.\nBut, a week later, the neurologist called and said he wasn’t sure that the hole was the cause of my stroked. He explained that doctors usually require both a hole and a hypercoagulable disease — i.e. you need a hole in your heart and a reason to have a clot. “Why the h*ll did you have me do this test, then?” I wanted to shout.\nTo make a long story short, I decided to go ahead and have surgery to close the hole. It’s not terribly risky, but it is heart surgery. I haven’t had another stroke in 12 years, I’ve had a very good neurologist tell me that clots sometimes form in the area right around the hole *just because*, I’ve had doctors tell me to get my head screwed on straight — everybody knows a hole isnt enough without a hypercoagulable disease … I’ve pretty much just given up having any chance of ever knowing what caused my strokes.\nSo please, figure it out! LOL"}
{"_id": "743822c2", "question": "Will a brain MRI reveal past strokes? If a stroke robust enough not to be considered a TIA were to occur, would it be visible in an MRI years later?", "answers": "I had a stroke, grand mal seizure which broke my back (L1 and L2) on 10/10/10….not a good day.\nMultiple CAT scans and MRI’s showed “moderate brain damage” from “prior strokes”. I had no knowledge of the prior strokes, but my Neurologist showed me the scans and said…”see all that white area….that’s damaged brain cells”….and there was a lot of white. I had a contrast MRI done which showed “recent” damage, based, I was told, on the amount of contrast that was taken up. Oddly, it was not as large as the original damage, but specifically located in the occipital region. This made sense since my stroke caused strange and scary visual disturbances.\nI was able to walk out of the hospital the next day, with aphasia, but otherwise seemingly OK. I asked the neurologist if I would be getting therapy for cognitive issues and he said “but you show no cognitive deficit”. In my addlebrained state, I accepted it…but I knew I was not the same.\nAnd here is the important part to people who may have had a stroke. Since only I seemed to be concerned about damage and it was not too apparent to others, I knew that I had to handle my recovery on my own (now I know I should have pushed to get professional help at that time, but I was not thinking clearly).\nI decided that I would meditate, play word games and play the guitar every day, since I had read that they help. Every day for about a year I spent 3–4 hours doing both and I am totally convinced that I am 98% recovered due to those efforts. I found Silva Systems tapes to be particularly soothing and helpful to my recovery.\nToday, nearly 7 years later most people can observe nothing that would be indicative of a stroke. I’ve developed “coping” mechanisms like double checking everything I write since I can no longer recognize homonyms (some results are humorous), I ask people “have I told you this before” and the answer is “yes” often, so I don’t repeat it. But I have no memory of having said it.\nI now also take about every “brain” supplement there is and I do find that some make a difference.\nSo my prior strokes, (and perhaps recent ones) are not apparent to me, but they are visible on MRI’s. But I believe that, in my case at least, that there are positive outcomes from a difficult situation."}
{"_id": "8613ba6e", "question": "In a four-stroke cycle, does the minimum temperature inside the engine cylinder occur at the beginning of the suction stroke or the end of the suction stroke?", "answers": "Because you have your intake cycle immediately after your combustion cycle, the cylinder head (internal) and valves are hotter now than at any other moment after the ignition flash.\nThe piston has just pushed out the hot exhaust gasses, which although less hot than the initial flaming of the air fuel mix are leaving a lot of their heat in the wall and head of the chamber, your engine is now, at inlet valve opening, sucking in “cold” air fuel mix, which has an immediate cooling effect on both the cylinder head and the cylinder wall, and also the piston head. Luckily it does, other wise your engine would melt.\nAt the Begining of the suction stroke, everything is hot, the air fuel mix comes in but has a lot of work to do cooling everything down. By the time it has sucked in a whole cylinder of air, the chamber cylinder temperature will be at its lowest point at the bottom of the cycle, the air fuel mix has been progressivly absorbing the heat as it comes in, as it does so, it expands, filling the cylinder more quickly than is desireable and resisting the in coming air fuel mix. So you will find that despite the suction of the piston as it descends, it is not getting a uniform amount of air coming in throughout the cycle.\nIn a badly set up engine, or one that is suffering from hot cylinders, you might even get the air fuel mixture to auto ignite, causing a “backfire” (more than one reason for backfires)\nSo, I’m pretty confident that you can take the moment of least temperature in the cylinder as being at bottom dead centre, where the air fuel mix has absorbed all of the heat energy from the cylinder that it can.\nThis is not a good thing for the efficiency of the engine, but a good thing for its cooling.\nThanks for the asking."}
{"_id": "9ea67eeb", "question": "What causes repeated TIA strokes? Are there any symptoms that occur ahead of a TIA?", "answers": "TIA = transient ischaemic attack, brief neurological symptoms that resolve fully (Scan shows no recent abnormality)\nStroke = symptoms don’t fully resolve within 24 hours (Scan shows recentabnormality)\nStrokes can be split into MINOR STROKE = can function independently despite deficits & MAJOR STROKE = needing help because of deficits.\nNOTE: TIAs are often called MINI-STROKES, causing some confusion with ‘minor’ stroke.\nAlso TIAs are often misdiagnosed (diagnosis is based on description of fleeting symptoms), so recurrent symptoms may be due to another cause (like hypoglycaemia in diabetics).\nTIA & stroke are caused by a blockage of blood flow to a part of the brain.\nRoughly speaking, duration of blockage predicts type of presentation. (Brief seconds > TIA; minutes > minor; permanent > major)\nAll indicate that something is wrong in the body causing a tendency to clot (prothrombotic), and thus risk of recurrence.\nTIA is the initial ‘warning’ symptom, and some (about 1 in 4) people have one or more TIA(s) before a stroke.\nRepeated TIAs indicate the need to consider…, if not already done (not an exhaustive list, but covers main issues):\nIs there disease in the carotid artery? “Carotid atheroma” - detectable by an ultrasound Doppler usually.\nIs there a cardiac arrhythmia? If not seen on an ECG, consider longer term cardiac monitoring to seek intermittent or paroxysmal irregularity.\nAre there risk factors that are poorly controlled? - e.g. current smoking, high blood pressure, high cholesterol, diabetes are the most prominent.\nAre the appropriate medications being prescribed and taken as prescribed?\nI would suggest a medical review to consider the above. Hope this helps.\nHave a look at the UK National Health Service webpage on TIA: Transient ischaemic attack (TIA)"}
{"_id": "6099f704", "question": "Is it possible for a heart attack and a stroke to occur at the same time?", "answers": "Yes, it is possible to have a heart attack (myocardial infarction) and a stroke (cerebrovascular infarction) at the same time. It is a very rare condition, which has been described as a “cardio-cerebral infarction”.\nIt is a very rare occurrence for an artery in the heart and an artery in the brain to both get obstructed due to rupture of their respective atheromatous plaques (that is rupture of the membrane which covers material such as oxidised cholesterol that has abnormally accumulated in the inner layer of the wall of the arteries in the process of the disease caused atherosclerosis). In most cases, the mechanism of a concurrent myocardial infarction and stroke is usually thromboembolic rather than atherosclerotic, meaning that the blood clots do not form independently at the two sites, but are detached pieces of a larger piece of blood clot which have travelled along with the blood stream.\nThe origin of such a thromboembolic event is usually a blood clot in the left side of the heart (the side which sends blood to organs such as the brain and the outer surface of the blood itself) due to a rhythm disorder (arrhythmia) called atrial fibrillation. Less commonly, it is a blood clot that has originally formed in the veins of the legs (deep vein thrombosis), which reaches the right side of the heart first (as the blood from most veins of the body does) and then gets squeezed into the left side of the heart through a hole in the septum separating the right from the left atrium (as in the so called patent foramen ovale).\nConcomitant acute right ventricular infarction and ischemic cerebrovascular\nstroke\n; possible explanations\nThere are no guidelines about what to do in case of a “hyperacaute simultaneous cardiocerebral infarction”, in patients presenting within the thrombolytic therapeutic window and with the possibility of a primary coronary intervention within 2 hours from diagnosis.\nHyperacute Simultaneous Cardiocerebral Infarction: Rescuing the Brain or the Heart First?\nIf the patient presents within a time frame of 4,5 hours from the onset of symptoms of a stroke (so called window of opportunity), it is possible to do thrombolysis (also called fibrinolytic therapy), that is to administer a medication that can dissolve the blood clot, without the risk of secondary bleeding (haemorrhagic complications) getting unacceptably high. Patients with strokes who present after 4,5 hours (for a certain type of strokes after 6 hours) from the onset of symptoms or where the onset of symptoms is uncertain, for example because they woke up with the symptoms after sleeping for more than 4,5 hours, are treated conservatively, because the bleeding risk from thrombolysis would be unacceptably high. A stroke due to bleeding (due to rupture or leak of an artery) can have the same or even more disastrous consequences as an ischaemic stroke (the latter being due to the obstruction of an artery).\nFor patients presenting within 12 (or up to 72) hours from onset of symptoms of a severe heart attack (an ST-elevation myocardial infarction, STEMI), there is a better alternative to thrombolysis: a primary coronary intervention (PCI), meaning that the doctor goes into the coronary artery with a catheter, dilates the narrow part (stenosis) with a balloon and places a stent that releases medication (drug eluting stent) which prevents a stenosis from happening again at the same site (re-stenosis). The combination of thrombolysis and coronary intervention carries a high bleeding risk, so thrombolysis is only done instead of primary coronary intervention (PCI) if the anticipated time until the patient reaches a PCI centre and gets the PCI done is longer than 2 hours from the diagnosis of the severe myocardial infarction (STEMI). That is because after 2 hours of not getting enough blood, so many heart muscle cells are dead or programmed for death, that it would have been better if the patient had been treated with thrombolysis and not primary coronary intervention, even if that means that he would not be able to get a coronary intervention with a catheter for another 24 hours.\nBut what to do with the patient presenting both with stroke and with ST-elevation myocardial infarction? Depending on the timing, a strategy might be to forego thrombolysis altogether and to perform primary coronary intervention on the coronary artery and (mechanical) endovascular embolectomy with a different catheter device on the cerebral artery, as explained in that case report:\nMANAGEMENT OF CONCURRENT CORTICAL\nSTROKE\nAND ST ELEVATION MYOCARDIAL INFARCTION WHEN PRESENTATION IS WITHIN THE WINDOW PERIOD: A CLINICAL CONUNDRUM"}
{"_id": "6859f12a", "question": "What are the long and short term effects of a stroke? What varying symptoms occur before and after a stroke survivor?", "answers": "I’m a stroke survivor. I know exactly how lucky I have been, but I still hate it.\nI had a right-side ischemic (clot) stroke with damage to the right posterior basal ganglia. The damage is small- only 1.2 cm across. The effects, though, are big.\nI did not lose consciousness nor have my cognitive abilities been damaged according to the Speech Language Pathologist. I could bear weight and had a reciprocal gait the next day. However—\nI had no idea where my left hand was- none. Once it was bent up behind me, and the nurse had to reposition because I was nearly laying on it, and didn’t know it wasn’t resting comfortably in front of me. If I held a cup of water in that hand and wasn’t looking at it every second, I would spill it- not from lack of strength, but because I didn’t know where it was and what position it was in, so the cup would tilt and spill. This is called proprioception- and I lost left side proprioception in a really weird way.\nThe loss in the upper limb- the hand- is pretty classic; the loss in the lower limb, hip to toes, was weird. Unlike not knowing where my foot was without looking, I lost bits and pieces of proprioception. For instance, I had my toes, but not my ankle. I could feel weight on my knee, but not my calf. My hip was all buggered up by it, with some muscles of the joint being known and others just along for the ride. In Therapy, they worked on strength so I could at least walk without a walker, but it took time to get all my bits and pieces back so I could do it correctly. I have stumped around like Igor for the past four months, but this past week, I seem to be getting back the last piece in my hip which is effecting the psoas muscle. Hooray for me!\nBut, I still hate it.\nI am no longer graceful- I was so graceful and competent. I moved swiftly and unerringly; I could walk two miles in 15 minutes; I could reach and bend and crouch and stretch and climb and move.\nNow I have to think about every move I make. I have to think when I walk- consciously think about each bit of the stride, chiding myself when my heel doesn’t strike the floor in the correct cadence, when I don’t push off with my toes hard enough, screwing up the gait. It is so tiring. It is so disheartening to have to do this, to have to be so super-aware of what used to be done naturally, with no thought, at all.\nI await the day I suddenly realize I haven’t had to think about all of this- I hope it comes soon.\nBut, I am lucky- very, very lucky. I could have lost the ability to swallow correctly, thus being on a feeding tube (worst case) or pureed mush diet for, well, ever. I could have lost the ability to speak, the larnyx frozen. I could have lost cognitive ability- as is, for the first couple months, it was as if the toy box where I held my stuff had been given a big shake; I knew I had whatever bit I needed, but had to sort through to find it again. But I could have lost all of it, I could have lost my life, so I am lucky.\nAnd all my therapists seem so surprised to learn I am only 4 months out from this stroke; “You’re already back at work?” “You don’t have to push so hard, you know”; yes, I do, because I know the earlier I get back, the more I get back, so it’s off to the races as far as I am concerned.\nThere was no precursor to my stroke. In fact, the whole episode took about 10 minutes- How do you stop a stroke while it’s happening? I’ve read some people feel dizzy sometimes, but there’s usually no sign it’s coming.\nWhich is why they can be so deadly.\nIf you are at risk for stroke, follow your doctor’s instructions- if you can get away from having this happen to you, you’ll be glad."}
{"_id": "0a959d4d", "question": "In a four stroke cycle, the minimum temperature inside the engine cylinder occurs at the?", "answers": "Minimum temperature occurs in suction stroke, when piston travels from TDC to BDC. See the following T-S diagram:"}
{"_id": "1cc02028", "question": "What are the symptoms, causes, and warning signs of a stroke that occurs in the human body?", "answers": "Symptoms\nIf you or someone you're with may be having a stroke, pay particular attention to the time the symptoms began. Some treatment options are most effective when given soon after a stroke begins.\nSigns and symptoms of stroke include:\n1 Trouble speaking and understanding what others are saying. You may experience confusion, slur your words or have difficulty understanding speech.\n2 Paralysis or numbness of the face, arm or leg. You may develop sudden numbness, weakness or paralysis in your face, arm or leg. This often affects just one side of your body. Try to raise both your arms over your head at the same time. If one arm begins to fall, you may be having a stroke. Also, one side of your mouth may droop when you try to smile.\n3 Problems seeing in one or both eyes. You may suddenly have blurred or blackened vision in one or both eyes, or you may see double.\n4 Headache. A sudden, severe headache, which may be accompanied by vomiting, dizziness or altered consciousness, may indicate that you're having a stroke.\n5 Trouble walking. You may stumble or lose your balance. You may also have sudden dizziness or a loss of coordination.\nCauses\nThere are two main causes of stroke: a blocked artery (ischemic stroke) or leaking or bursting of a blood vessel (hemorrhagic stroke). Some people may have only a temporary disruption of blood flow to the brain, known as a transient ischemic attack (TIA), that doesn't cause lasting symptoms.\n1 Ischemic stroke\nIschemic strokeOpen pop-up dialog box\nThis is the most common type of stroke. It happens when the brain's blood vessels become narrowed or blocked, causing severely reduced blood flow (ischemia). Blocked or narrowed blood vessels are caused by fatty deposits that build up in blood vessels or by blood clots or other debris that travel through your bloodstream and lodge in the blood vessels in your brain.\nSome initial research shows that COVID-19 infection may be a possible cause of ischemic stroke, but more study is needed.\n2 Hemorrhagic stroke:\nHemorrhagic stroke occurs when a blood vessel in your brain leaks or ruptures. Brain hemorrhages can result from many conditions that affect your blood vessels. Factors related to hemorrhagic stroke include:\nUncontrolled high blood pressure\nOvertreatment with blood thinners (anticoagulants)\nBulges at weak spots in your blood vessel walls (aneurysms)\nTrauma (such as a car accident)\nProtein deposits in blood vessel walls that lead to weakness in the vessel wall (cerebral amyloid angiopathy)\nIschemic stroke leading to hemorrhage\nA less common cause of bleeding in the brain is the rupture of an abnormal tangle of thin-walled blood vessels (arteriovenous malformation).\nTransient Ischemic Stroke:\nA transient ischemic attack (TIA) — sometimes known as a ministroke — is a temporary period of symptoms similar to those you'd have in a stroke. A TIA doesn't cause permanent damage. They're caused by a temporary decrease in blood supply to part of your brain, which may last as little as five minutes.Like an ischemic stroke, a TIA occurs when a clot or debris reduces or blocks blood flow to part of your nervous system.Seek emergency care even if you think you've had aTIA because your symptoms got better. It's not possible to tell if you're having a stroke or TIAbased only on your symptoms. If you've had a TIA, it means you may have a partially blocked or narrowed artery leading to your brain. Having TIA increases your risk of having a full-blown stroke later."}
{"_id": "5a3cb4bd", "question": "In a 4-stroke gasoline engine, how many times does spark occur in a cycle?", "answers": "Traditionaly discounting single cylinder engines, a spark occurs every second crankshaft turn at or just before TDC at the end of the compression stroke.\nMost single cylinder engines and some vehicles with shared coils between cylinders which are one crankshaft turn away can have a spark firing at the end of the exhaust stroke as well as at the end of the compression stroke. The extra spark does nothing on the end of the exhaust stroke. An example of a car engine which has a V6 engine with 3 coils and the plugs fire every revolution is the 3.8litre GM V6 used in the Holden Commodore. The firing order for this engine is 1–2–3–4–5–6. The opposing cylinder fired with number 1 is 4, 2 with 5 and 3 with 6. All Briggs and Stratton, Honda, Subaru and a number of unbranded Chinese lawnmower engines fire every crankshaft turn as they have no distributor and the flywheel leaves no room to place a trigger mechanism on the end of the camshaft. It would also be a pain to service unless there were windows in the flywheel."}
{"_id": "dd4b625d", "question": "How many ignition events occur for every 360 degree rotation of the crankshaft in a 4 cylinder, 4 stroke engine?", "answers": "Two “ignition events” take place but in two different cylinders. An easy way to understand this is to remember that the distributor in a 4 stroke 4 cylinder engine sends out a spark every 90 degrees of the distributor, the second thing to remember is that the distributor turns at half the speed of the crankshaft, this means that when the crankshaft did 360 degrees (one full revolution) the distributor did only 180 degrees (half a revolution), thus it went through two 90 degrees intervals and therefor supplied two sparks for the “ignition events” or firing strokes/power strokes."}
{"_id": "5bd05b02", "question": "In Otto cycle, when the 1st compression stroke is occurring where is it receiving work to do the compression stroke?", "answers": "During compression it uses power from previous cycles which is stored in flywheel.\nFor very first,starting of engine starting motor is use to supply power during compression.\nSimilarly for kick start , lever moves the piston creating compression stroke.(keep in mind that piston has to be in particular position to start the engine,this is is reason engine does for every kick)"}
{"_id": "b8fc80b7", "question": "How many diseases can occur due to a stroke?", "answers": "Its not a matter of getting diseases from a stroke. The stroke can affect any part of your body. With strokes it is how severely a person is affected. This can vary enormously. Mini strokes do not usually do so much harm. A major stroke could disable you for life. There are many degrees of seriousness in between. Any stroke has to be taken seriously though. A person can get a series of strokes. If a person suffers from any stroke, then certain life changes need to be made in order to avoid getting any more. If you are very lucky then it may not do permanent damage. Sometimes people recover, and regain their faculties. Unfortunately this is not always the case. There's no way of predicting how much harm a stroke may do. There are ways to avoid them, by living a healthy lifestyle."}
{"_id": "a9e943e3", "question": "Was it a master stroke by Modi Government in passing the EBC bill in LS and such thought never occurred by earlier governments?", "answers": "This was attempted by PVN when Mandal commission recommendations were implemented. SC struck down saying that economic backwardness alone can not be basis for reservations. Gujarati govt. tried this before recent elections and was set aside by Gujarati high court. This is a old wine in an old bottle.\nLike Ram Mandir this is another ploy to gain political advantage in 2019 elections. Govt. jobs are few and the demand for jobs can only be met by creation of jobs in private sector. Having failed to do this, Govt. has taken a dangerous path that may boomerang.\nThe proposal classifies those earning Rs 8,00,000/- as economically backward and provides reservation in Govt. jobs. But why is the Govt. not exempting these poor people from income tax by raising income tax threshold to Rs 800000/-?\nAgain those owning more than 5 acres of agricultural land are not eligible for reservations. Does Govt. think that farmers owning 6 acres and above earn net income of Rs 800000/- making them ineligible for reservations?\nAll this shows that this is not being done with good intent to help people and is being done hastily without consultations.\nJ"}
{"_id": "ec6d10ae", "question": "Does a 4-stroke gasoline engine spark occur two times in a cycle?", "answers": "It depends upon the type of ignition system used. A wasted spark ignition system will fire every time the Piston approaches top dead center. Even when the Piston is coming up on the exhaust stroke, the spark plug will still fire, even though the spark is of no value. This is done to make a cost-effective ignition system. This is very common in single cylinder, 4-stroke engines and automobile engines when they first went away from distributor style ignition systems in the 1980s."}
{"_id": "0acad399", "question": "What do we mean by saying that the compression ratio in a dual combustion cycle is 16 and the cutoff occurs at 2% of the stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "962a8301", "question": "What are some common sensations that occur before a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ca2b3ec7", "question": "I know the warning signs of a stroke. But can symptoms come and go ahead of time? Like months post for the stroke actually occurs?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "315583e2", "question": "How much after angioplasty should I expect another stroke to occur?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f58019a1", "question": "I have seen in the news recently that neck cracking can cause stroke. Does this occur only when your neck is manipulated to crack, or can it happen when your neck cracks naturally?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d9e23fb4", "question": "Do most repeat strokes usually occur on the same side of the brain as the first?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4f000488", "question": "Is it very surprising that people don't take covid-19 restrictions very seriously when dramatic reversals like this are occurring, apparently at the stroke of a pen?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f2ce0f88", "question": "What can occur from a loose exhaust on a 2-stroke motorbike?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ba150a59", "question": "Are seizures likely to occur 7 months after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "cb7a6d76", "question": "What is a stroke? Why does it occur? What is its treatment?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "23f17d06", "question": "Neurosurgery: What is the cure for MCA infarct damage occurring after a brain stroke?", "answers": "Sorry about your father. The information you offered is not sufficient to elaborately evaluate the prognosis of your father. Unfortunately persistent coma is not a good sign for favourable prognosis. Listening to your doctor and coordinating with him as well as you can is suggested."}
{"_id": "830520d3", "question": "Can dizziness occur after treatment for a cerebral stroke?", "answers": "Yes. Many cases are related with areas of brain which control balance. Those may get affected in several ways resulting in dizziness. Stroke may not be a easy matter. A person should always accompany the patient to prevent fall.\nOf course there are other reasons than it. Follow up treating medicine doctor in real life is very important. Take the matter seriously till treating doctor ensure safety, provide you tips. Many family members confuse such with weakness after sickness."}
{"_id": "b46b26a0", "question": "What is the average lenghth of time between suffering an Transient Ischemic Stroke and the occurence of a major stroke?", "answers": "A TIA often precedes a major ischemic stroke by a month or less. Prompt assessment of a TIA and following medical recommendations may prevent further problems.\nMy radiologist found signs that I’d suffered TIA’s that I wasn’t aware of in his assessment of the CT I had when I first arrived with a major stroke. I wish I’d noticed and paid attention.\nStrokes leave permanent damage and recovery is very difficult. It has been almost three years of hard work and I’m still recovering. Everyone remarks on my “remarkable” recovery, but I’m still clumsy, off balance and I fall far too often.\nIf you have a TIA, pay attention!"}
{"_id": "45eb3f7a", "question": "How much time does it take to occur a brain stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f24e8d02", "question": "Can you explain the four stroke cycle and two stroke cycle that occur perpendicular?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6eadded1", "question": "How long can a mini stroke be detected after it occurs?", "answers": "If you've had a stroke, it's likely that it won't show up on a CT scan of your brain for 24 to 48 hours. An MRI scan usually shows a stroke sooner. In evaluating the cause of the ministroke or stroke, your doctor will likely order an ultrasound to see if there's significant blockage or plaque in your carotid arteries."}
{"_id": "86bad797", "question": "Is it true that the back/reverse torque effect, what we usually call engine braking, during deceleration doesn't occur in a 4-stroke engine with slipper clutch?", "answers": "Engine braking is still there, but the slipper clutch prevents it from being too pronounced or abrupt. Think about it as ABS of sorts - it will still brake, but will prevent wheel lockup."}
{"_id": "f9ef38a3", "question": "Why does cough occur when drinking water in stroke-affected patients?", "answers": "Majority of stroke survivors experience dysphagia( difficulty in swallowing) after a stroke event. Swallowing is a complicated task which needs the brain co-ordinate a lot of muscles. Since the stroke affects the brain, it causes inability to swallow the food entering the oesophagus. When a person aspirates, while they are swallowing, it accidentally enters thier airway and lungs. This triggers the coughing reaction. Most of the stroke patients will not be present with a cough reflex, they would have aspiration since the sensation reduces.\nWhat you can do about it:\nThere are a variety of swallowing exercises which can help stroke patients symptomatically from difficulty in swallowing.\nYawning: Open the jaw as far as he can for 10 seconds. Rest for 5 seconds. Do 5 repeats for 2 times a day. This action promotes upper movement of the larynx ( voice box) and the esophagus.\nEffortful Swallow: let him imagine to have a marble stuck in his throat. Educate him to squeeze as hard as he can with his throat muscles. Do 5 repeats for 2 times a day. This improve the movement of tongue base and pharynx.\nResistive tongue exercise: Pushing the tongue hard against the roof of the mouth.Push tongue hard against each cheek. Push strong hard against a tongue depressor or spoon. Hold for 10 seconds. Do 5 repeats for 2 times a day. This improve tongue strength and control of food and drink.\nEpiglottic control: Improve airway protection when you swallow. Open your mouth wide. Exhale the air from your lungs, but do not allow any air to escape from your mouth. Your airway should remain closed. You will be exhaling against a closed throat so air cannot escape. Hold for 10 seconds. Do 5 reps 2 times per day.\nNeed Patience With The Patient: It may be hard to co-operate with a patient and even harder if he/ she is elder. Stroke patients will have anxiety and depression symptoms too. So make sure that you are patient enough and not expecting for a quick fix.\nResults will be slow but these exercises will take care to not worsen the symptoms. Discuss about this with your doctor too cuz I am aware of the patient's previous history.\nUpvote my answer if it helped you!"}
{"_id": "666d02b2", "question": "In multi-cylinder engine arrangement, are the cylinders so arranged that the power stroke in all the cylinders never occurs simultaneously?", "answers": "There would be no point in designing virtually a single cylinder engine with multiple cylinders. The whole point of multiple cylinders and pistons is to distribute the power smoothly so that a large flywheel is not needed to smooth the engine vibrations. The reciprocating mass of each piston is less in a multi cylinder engine, so there is that balance advantage, but it is the reduction of vibration and smooth acceleration that is required for a car. This is better suited to staggered power strokes. Also, if the pistons were arranged so that several power strokes occurred simultaneously, there would be repercussions on the camshaft by opening and closing two sets of valve springs at once. There probably were attempts in the past to play around with designs, but the ones that are the best are still in production today, and none of them have simultaneous power strokes in modern automobiles.\nThere are radial 2 stroke engines such as the Hiness 3 Cylinder two-stroke radial that did have simultaneous power strokes, but they are not used as automobile engines."}
{"_id": "80af065c", "question": "Why does the first flaccidity occur in a stroke then after spasticity?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a3a25b26", "question": "What type of disease can occur during problems in nervous systems?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "078f15ff", "question": "Do false negatives for posterior stroke mainly occur with MRI in the early stages?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "62823dbf", "question": "Could a standard MRI detect a brain hemorrhage or stroke which occurred a couple weeks ago, or what would be the best way to diagnose it?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "33e01dc5", "question": "Can scorpion bite be complicated by ischaemic stroke? If so, how does this occur?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "dac3c0ad", "question": "When does the minimum temperature in a four-stroke cycle occur inside the engine cylinder?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1a5c0320", "question": "Why do false negatives in MRI occur for strokes in the posterior portion of the brain? How likely do you think this is to happen?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7e3d9537", "question": "Does the indicator diagram occur any change if we reverse a 2-stroke low speed diesel engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1b79845d", "question": "How often do CRVO eye strokes cause complete irreversible blindness in the eye that they occur in?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "309cc2aa", "question": "How do you find the max temperature and pressure of a dual cycle engine and the percentage of stroke at which the cutoff occurs?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c08c95d0", "question": "What does it mean that in stroke, paralysis occurs on the side of the body opposite to cerebral infarct?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2afe32b4", "question": "Does any sensation occur in our nervous system when we get a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4e248b3a", "question": "What progress has occurred in restoring left or right peripheral vision loss due to a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4591f08e", "question": "When a brain stroke already occured, can Ecosprin can be given? It acts as blood thinner. So can it causes more bleeding inside brain?", "answers": "When evaluating a person for stroke remember the mnemonic FAST:\nFace drooping\nArm weakness\nSpeech difficulty\nTime to call\nIt is best to think of a stroke as a “brain attack. “ Time is of the essence. If the person you are evaluating has any one of the above signs, call 911 and inform the operator you believe that you may have a person with a stroke. As to aspirin, there are two kind of strokes hemorrhagic and ischemic. with out a CT scan or MRI, it would be impossible to determine which type of stroke the person is having. Giving aspirin could actually make matters worse in a hemorrhagic stroke. Don’t waste time!"}
{"_id": "2a85e0b3", "question": "30 months ago I had a left brain frontal lobe hemorrhagic stroke. I now experience bouts of muscular aching in my shoulder and hip, usually accompanied by low level twitching. What are these? Why are they occurring now?", "answers": "Now you just have to know that I’m going to tell you that it would be a good idea to make an appointment with your Neurologist. The Frontal Lobes are usually thought of as the control center for our judgement and emotions but it does have an involvement with motor function. What you are describing could be related to your stroke or it could be something new arriving on the scene. It could be minor or it could be major, but the important thing is to check it out. There are many conditions today that improve with medical intervention and as scary as I’m sure that stroke was, the fact that you can type up a question on a computer and submit it shows that your frontal lobes are hanging in there. But as you probably heard with your stroke the medical community says, time is brain, so go check it out sooner rather than later."}
{"_id": "bd778699", "question": "My grand mother had a stroke 3 days back but is showing signs of memory losses today, is that normal to occur after 3 days?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7e080fc8", "question": "When someone gently strokes the hairs on the back of your neck, you feel a tingling sensation. Can you explain why this occurs?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "20215770", "question": "Why is it that strokes that occur in patients with Sickle Cell Anaemia mostly arise from clumps in larger arteries as opposed to smaller arteries? Wouldn't the clumping of sickle cells decrease blood flow to the brain greater in the smaller arteries?", "answers": "My Guess (I’m a lab guy, not a doctor) is that sickle cells are activated in venous blood because of the low oxygen and plug the lung microcirculation and the lung complains by releasing clotting products (Tissue Thromboplastin) that harm the heart and/or the brain."}
{"_id": "5c704415", "question": "After a stroke which processes occur in damaged brain tissues? I mean from a point when tissues suffer from hypoxia to a recovery stage when a brain adapts to it's new condition. Which complications could a patient get?", "answers": "I’m not sure what you’re looking for. I had a hemorrhage in my brain (hemorrhagic stroke). They watched me closely for about 24 hours looking for signs of pressure inside the cranium that would require emergency surgery. Then they did another CT scan to check whether the bleeding had stopped. If it hadn’t stopped, I would have needed surgery to stop it.\nA Speech Therapist tested my ability to swallow on the 2nd day. I’d had nothing by mouth at that point. My swallowing was not perfect, so they put me on thickened liquids (yuck!) and soft foods. They didn’t want me to aspirate food or drink and develop bacterial pneumonia.\nMy blood pressure was sky high during the acute stroke, and they lowered it very slowly to avoid shocking the brain with the change in pressure. I was in ICU for two weeks until my BP was under 160. Then, I was transferred to a critical care telemetry unit.\nThe blood that had leaked into my brain had burst into one of the ventricles and displaced the cerebrospinal fluid that normally fills the ventricles. The blood drained slowly into my spine, causing a ferocious headache that lasted over a week. The headache was painful, but harmless.\nThe nurses watched over the side that was paralyzed. They carefully positioned my “useless” arm on a pillow. They kept my “dead” leg covered and warm. I couldn’t feel anything on that side, so the nurses were making sure I did not harm myself by getting into a position that cut off blood flow to a limb.\nMy affected arm hung like dead weight from my shoulder. It pulled on the shoulder joint all the way across to my neck. I couldn’t feel anything except the deep pain of the strained muscles or tendons, but it felt nice when the nurses rubbed liniment into the area. They placed my arm on a pile of pillows to support it and protect the shoulder joint.\nThat is about all I remember about complications in my case, but when I got to rehab and worked in groups of stroke survivors, I saw that many of them had ugly craniotomy incisions. A craniotomy has many risks of complications as well, though since I didn’t need one (thank goodness!)I don’t know what they are.\nIn my first week of rehab, I was assessed for deficits. They tested my limbs, my eyesight, my sensation, my strength, etc. They also tested me for cognitive deficits in memory, attention, executive function, and other things."}
{"_id": "0a98b97e", "question": "What occurs in each combustion chamber during the operation of a 4-stroke cycle Otto engine?", "answers": "The fuel air mixture will swirl around the combustion chamber as the piston rises to compress it. Just before the piston is at the top of the cylinder the spark plug will ignite the mixture and a very fast burn and expansion of the mixtures occurs. This expansion pushes the piston down on the power stroke. How cleanly and completely the fuel burns is a function of the combustion chamber and inlet manifold design. Please note there is no explosion just an extremely fast controlled expansion."}
{"_id": "b6e72530", "question": "Why do strokes occur without symptoms?", "answers": "Stroke : Sudden focal neurological deficit due to vascular etiology\nTypes : Ischemic(85%) and Hemorrhagic\nIschemic Stroke : It happens when an obstruction (clot) suddenly interrupts the blood flow to an area of the brain causing sudden focal neurological deficits. These symptoms vary depending on the area involved. So by definitino stroke can not be defined without clinical symptoms.\nIn patients patients who have some neurological symptoms might get a brain imaging. Those images might reveal evidence suggesting areas of brain damaged in a pattern consistent with a stroke.\nRegardless of symptosms, the radiological findings should alert the physicain to look for vascular disease and a treatment plan."}
{"_id": "700309ed", "question": "How do you treat heat stroke?", "answers": ""}
